In 1927, the lawyer Cesare Buscaglia from Genoa
En 1927, el abogado Cesare Buscaglia de Génova
wrote a letter
escribió una carta
to Ernesto Schiaparelli
a Ernesto Schiaparelli
who at the time was director of the Museum of Antiquities in Turin
quien en ese momento dirigía el Museo de Antigüedades de Turín
offering as a gift
ofreciéndole como donación
two important
dos importantes
antiquities from the island of Santo Domingo
antigüedades procedentes de la isla de Santo Domingo
Schiaparelli in turn wrote
Schiaparelli, a su vez, escribió
to the Minister of Public Education
al ministro de Instrucción Pública
Pietro Fedele, requesting authorization
Pietro Fedele, solicitando autorización
to acquire these two objects
para adquirir estos dos objetos
authorization which the minister granted
autorización que el ministro concedió
in a letter addressed to Schiaparelli
respondiendo a Schiaparelli
which arrived
con una carta que llegó
just a few days before his death
pocos días antes de su muerte
which occurred on February 14, 1928
que ocurrió el 14 de febrero de 1928
At that point
en ese momento
the objects arrived in Turin
los objetos llegaron a Turín
and were acquired
y fueron adquiridos
by the Museum of
por el Museo de
Anthropology and Ethnography of the University
Antropología y Etnografía de la Universidad
directed by Giovanni Marro
dirigido por Giovanni Marro
who exhibited them
quien los exhibió
at the museum's original location in Palazzo Carignano
en la primera sede del Palazzo Carignano
and later also at the next location
y luego también en la sede siguiente
in the former San Giovanni Battista Hospital
en el antiguo hospital San Giovanni Battista
as part of a scenographic display built with a
dentro de una escenografía construida con un
small Peruvian temple
templete peruano
without realizing the
sin darse cuenta de la
origin and the
procedencia y la
extraordinary significance of these two objects
extraordinaria relevancia de estos dos objetos